A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) files FA740
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant Awardees – Multi-Institutional (not Fund Administered), 1944-1966; III; 115.2 Cubic Feet 96 boxes.
  - High School Teachers Fellowship Program, 1951-1966; 8; 22.8 Cubic Feet 19 boxes.; 19 boxes.
    - HSTFP, 1955-1956
      - Bell, Collins J. - Wilbur Wright High School - Dayton, Ohio, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Benson, Wendell - Roosevelt High School - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Bongarzone, Elito - Natick High School - Framingham, Massachusetts, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Bottrell, Helen - Jackson Junior High School - Pasadena, Texas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Bredehorn, Marjorie L. - Thacker Junior High School - Des Plaines, Illinois, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Brodin, Dorothy - Hunter College High School - New York, NY, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Brown, Evelyn A. - R. B. Hudson High School - Selma, Alabama, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Burnside, Opal J. - Baldwin Junior High School - Montgomery, Alabama, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Cade, Carol Elizabeth - El Dorado Junior High School - El Dorado, Arkansas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Campbell, Douglas - Santa Rosa High School - Santa Rosa, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Campbell, Robert - Nott Terrace High School - Schenectady, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Carlson, Thelma Agnes - Bisbee High School - Bisbee, Arizona, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Chiaramonte, Michael Peter - Southold High School - Shelter Island Heights, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Christian, Ruby Elinor - Roosevelt Junior High School - San Diego, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Cohen, Caryl E. - Girls High School - New York City, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Cook, Thomas C. - Lakewood High School - Lakewood, Ohio, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Cottingham, George Ann - Eastern Junior High School - Louisville, Kentucky, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Cowley, Edward - The Milne High School - Albany, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Cummins, Bonnie J. - Midland High School - Midland Texas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Dean, James - Tomlinson Vocational High School - Clearwater, Florida, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Doane, Raymond C. - Central High School - St. Paul, Minnesota, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Donlon, Cynthia - Oxnard Union High School - Oxnard, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Drake, Robert M. - Lincoln Junior High School - Santa Monica, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Duckett, Randall Harrison - West Buncombe High School - Asheville, North Carolina, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Duckett, Sybil S. - West Buncombe High School - Asheville, North Carolina (Box 14 (49701))
      - Ellis, Edward H. - Everett High School - Everett, Washington, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Fiers, Alan R. - Folwell Junior High School - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Flatow, Eleanor R.C. - Gove Junior High School - Denver, Colorado, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Follin, Virginia E. - John Adams High School - Cleveland, Ohio, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Francis, Helen - George Washington Junior High School - Long Beach, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Garrett, Lottie Ree - Pintlala Junior High School - Montgomery, Alabama, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Gilbert, Janet M. - La Salle High School - Niagara Falls, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Golden, Ruth I. - Northeastern High School - Detroit, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Gordon, Erwin E. - Abraham Lincoln High School - San Francisco, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Greenley, Bess M. - Oelwein High School - Oelwein, Iowa, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Griffin, Margaret Bell - Butler Junior High School - Kentucky, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Guerrero, Gloria M. - Agana Junior High School - Agana, Guam, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Guerrero, Betty Sur - George Washington High School - Agana, Guam, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hall, George W. - Central High School - Tulsa, Oklahoma, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Harrold, John P. - Midland Senior High School - Midland, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hardy, Kay Ridgway - Fern Creek High School - Louisville, Kentucky (Box 14 (49701))
      - Harwood, William Benton - Bakersfield High School - Bakersfield, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hatch, Louis - High Point High School - High Point, North Carolina, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hathaway, Howard Higbee - Murray High School - Murray High School - St. Paul, Minnesota, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hazard, Patrick D. - East Lansing High School - East Lansing, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Henry, Mabel C.W. - Wilmington High School - Wilmington, Delaware, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hight, William B. Jr. - Altamahaw Ossipee High School - Altamahaw, North Carolina, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hills, Richard Blair - Edison High School - Gary, Indiana, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hodges, Lucile - Lithonia High School - Lithonia, Georgia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hofkin, Fred M. - South Philadelphia High School for Boys - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Holland, Mary E. - Montclair High School - Montclair, New Jersey, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hornac, Emmelene - Royal Oak Senior High School - Royal Oak, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Hundall, Jack P. - Edison High School - Seattle, Washington, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Johnson, James T. Jr. - West Denver High School - Denver, Colorado, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Jurgielewicz, Vincent - F.A. Day Junior High School - Newton, Massachusetts, 1955 - 1956 (Box 14 (49701))
      - Kirkwood, Virginia - William Flemming High School - Roanoke, Virginia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Klein, Milton M. - Evander Childs High School - New York City, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Knepp, Thomas H. - Stroudsburg High School - Stroudsburg, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Koegel, Louise V. - Scarsdale High School - Scarsdale, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Koff, Anne - New Rochelle High School - New Rochelle, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Krause, Marcella - McChesney High School - Oakland, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Landis, Sarah E. - Bailey Junior High School - Jackson, Mississippi, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Lane, Mary R. - Bulkeley High School - Hartford, Connecticut, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Langston, Virginia L. - Bolton High School - Pineville, Louisiana, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Larkin, Myrtle S. - Herkimer High School - Herkimer, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Law, Richard B. - Mansfield High School - Medway, Massachusetts, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Lee, Elizabeth M. - Hayward High School - Hayward, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Long, Pauline King - Woodlawn High School - Birmingham, Alabama, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Lynch, Emily M. - O'Keefe High School - Atlanta, Georgia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Lyon, Mildred Hardin - Midwest City Senior High School - Midwest, Oklahoma, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McAlvey, K. Dale - Petoskey High School - Petoskey, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McCarthy, Kathleen - South Philadelphia High School for Girls, 1955- 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McConarty, Elizabeth M. - North Quincy High School - Wollaston, Massachusetts, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McGouirk, Joyce G. - Douglas City Schools - Douglas, Georgia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McKinney, William Preston - North Salem High School - Salem, Oregon, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McMath, Virginia C. - Eastern High School - Louisville, Kentucky, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - McRoberts, Walter C. - LeRoy Central School - LeRoy, N.Y., 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Marcell, James E. - Lincoln Junior High School - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Maupin, Milburn T. - DuValle Junior High School - Louiville, Kentucky, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Messinger, Henry C. - Allentown High School - Allentown, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Meyer, Mathilda E. - South Hills High School - Pittsburgh, PA, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Millin, Agnes Alethea - Charotte Amalie High School - St.Thomas, Virgin Islands, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Mitchell, Wanda B. - Evanston Township High School - Evanston, Illinois, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Moody, Mary A. - Rankin High School - Greensboro, North Carolina, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Mustonen, Mabel V. - Cass Tech High School - Detroit, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Mutton, Helen - Gross Pointe High School - Grosse Point Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Nettleton, Leon D. - Pleasantville High School - Pleasantville, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Norem, Agnes E. - Antigo Junior Senior High School - Antigo, Wisconsin, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Ochoa, Frank J. - Woodrow Wilson High School - Long Beach, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Pace, Nora R. - Martinsville High School - Martinsville, Virginia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Pelton, Helen - Walnut Hills High School - Cincinnati, Ohio, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Perrill, Ariel S. - Hutchinson High School - Hutchinson, Kansas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Podany, George - Longfellow School - Flint, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Pursinger, Marvin Gavin, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Raawe, Irene E. - Rice Lake High School - Rice Lake, Wisconsin, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Raines, David - Mount Lebanon High School - Mount Lebanon, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Raub, Stanley L. - Middletown High School - Middletown, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Rilliet, Vivian F. - Woodrow Wilson High School - Long Beach, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Roeder, Virginia V. - William S. Baer School - Baltimore, Maryland, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Rucker, Blanche P. - Weatherford Junior High School - Weatherford, Texas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Ryder, Thomas E. - Lower Merion Senior High School - Villanova, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Savoca, Anthony F. - C.J. Colton Jr. High School - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Scappucci, Charlotte - Central High School - Charlotte, North Carolina, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Schaeffer, John Roy - Capuchino High School - Los Altos, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 15 (49702))
      - Smith, Euris Maria - AE Beach High School - Savannah, Georgia, 1953 - 1954 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Sommers, Wesley Sherran - Cadillac High School - Cadilac, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Spahr, Phil S. - Kingwood High School - Kingwood, Virginia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Stancil, Mildred L. - Jordan Vocational High School - Columbia, Georgia, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Stauffer, George F. - Sharon Hill High School - Lansdowne, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Stein, Charles W. - HC Technical High School - Buffalo, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Stephenson, Mary Jane - Sharon School District - Sharon, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Stern, Jack - Central High School - Charlotte, North Carolina, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Stevens, Bernice A. - Francis Joseph reitz High School - Evansville, Indiana, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Strauss, Samuel - McKinley High School - Washington, DC, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Surbaugh, Nelvada - Independence High School - Independence, Missouri, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Tarry, Hazel - North Chattanooga Junior High School - Chattanooga, Tennessee, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Theobald, Ronald Wilson - Miami Senior High School - Miami, Florida, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Tuggle, Samuel P., Jr. - Whitehaven High School - Capleville, Tennessee, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Turner, George - Claremont High School - Claremont, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Ushijima, Toshiko - Hilo High School - Honolulu, Hawaii, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Ulm, Murray B. - Fairbanks High School - Fairbanks, Alaska, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Wagner, Daniel - New Rochelle High School - New Rochelle, New York, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Warner, Truman A. - Briarcliff High School, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Waters, Mary Louise - Newton High School - Newton, Massachusetts, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Weckstein, Abraham M. - Barringer High School - Newark, New Jersey, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Weiherman, Eleanor M. - Plytechnic High School - Long Beach, California, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Weier, Leona - Gross Pointe High School - Gross Pointe, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Wernecke, Margaret - Washington Park High School - Racine, Wisconsin, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Whaling, Delphine - Rocky River High School - Rocky River, Ohio, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Wilhelm, Marjorie Bell - Natrona County High School - Casper, Wyoming, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Wilke, Gerhard Max - Technical High School - Springfield, Massachusetts, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Winston, Mary Louise - McLean Junior High School - Fort Worth, Texas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Wood, Norma Lynn - Houston Public Schools - Houston, Texas, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Woodward, Margaret Ruth - Marhsall Junior High School - Houston, Texas, 1954 - 1955 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Young, Anthony KC - Kalakaua Intermediate School - Honolulu, Hawaii, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Zaragoza Melendez, Juanita - Doctor Pila High School - Ponce, Puerto Rico, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Group Application - Ruth Winter, Louis Calfin, Ethel Tincher - Detroit, Michigan, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Group Application - Modesta Berry, Kathryn Carney, Elizabeth Keltz - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Group Application - Helen Arbes, Dorothy Green, Mary Pilch - St. Paul, Minnesota, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Group Application - Andrew Beeler, James Porter - Louisville, Kentucky, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Group Applications - Correspondence, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
      - Group Application - Wade B. Fleetwood, Robert C. Woodward - Boise, Idaho, 1955 - 1956 (Box 16 (49703))
    - Administration, 1952 - 1955
      - Announcements - 1955 to 1956, 1955 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Announcements - 1954 to 1955, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Announcements - 1953 to 1954, 1953 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Announcements - 1952 to 1953, 1952 - 1953 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Distribution Statistics - 1953 to 1954, 1953 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Distribution Statisitics - 1952 to 1954, 1952 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Distribution Statistics - 1952 to 1953, 1952 - 1953 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Evaluation - Complaints, 1952 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Evaluation - Minutes, 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Evaluation - Reports, 1952 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Forum, 1953 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Information Memo, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - National Committee - Meeting - August 1952 (Box 17 (49704))
      - National Committee - Regions 1 through 5, 1955 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - National Committee - Regions 6 through 9, 1955 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Policy and Procedure - National Education Association, 1953 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Policy and Procedure - Planning, 1952 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Policy and Procedure - Staff Meetings, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Policy and Procedure - Tax Information [CONFIDENTIAL], 1952 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Press Release - December 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Press Release - December 1953 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Press Release - June 3, 1953 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Press Release - September 1952 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Press Release - July 1952 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Publicity, 1952 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Regional Committees - Correspondence, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Regional Committees - Lists, 1955 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Regional Committees - Memo for Screening and Selection, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Statistics on Fellows and Programs - 1955 to 1956, 1955 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Statistics on Fellows and Programs - 1954 to 1955, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Statistics on Fellows and Programs - 1953 to 1954, 1953 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Statistics on Fellows and Programs - 1952 to 1953, 1952 - 1953 (Box 17 (49704))
    - Winners, 1952 - 1956
      - Winners - 1952 to 1953, 1952 - 1953 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Winners - 1953 to 1954, 1953 - 1954 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Winners - 1954 to 1955, 1954 - 1955 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Winners - 1955 to 1956, 1955 - 1956 (Box 17 (49704))
      - Winners - 1955 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1955 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1954 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1953 (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - A (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - B (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - C (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - D (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - F (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - G (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - H (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - I (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - J (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - K (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - L (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - M (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - N (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - O (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - P (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - R (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - S (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - T (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - V (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - W (Box 18 (49705))
      - Winners - 1952 - Y (Box 18 (49705))
      - H.S.T Fellowship General Info, 1954-1955
      - H.S.T. Fellowship Program Meeting, April 15-18, 1955
      - H.S.T Fellowship Program Meeting, April 1-3, 1955
      - High School Meeting, April 1955
      - H.S.T Fellowship Program Meeting, April 2-4, 1954
      - H.S.T. Fellowship Reports, 1953-1954
    - Grant Awardee Cards, 1951-1966
      - Unfoldered individual forms of each school awarded grants., 1951-1966 (Box 19 (49706))
  - Institute for Philosophical Research, 1952-1959; 9; 1.2 Cubic Feet 1 box.; 1 box.
    The Institute for Philosophical Research sub-series contains information about the work of Mortimer J. Adler and his staff of the Institute for Philosophical Research. The Institute sought to extract from over 2,000 years of writings the development of the basic ingredients of human thought, the "Great Ideas." The files are comprised of correspondence exchanged between Mortimer and Clarence Faust. The following publications are included in the sub-series: The Controversy Concerning Human Freedom, Parts I-IV and The Capitalist Manifesto.
    - Conferences in Europe, 1954 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Forum on Freedom, Nov. 30 - Dec. 1, 1953 (Box 1 (49707))
    - General correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 1 (49707))
    - General data [2 Folders], 1953-1959 (Box 1 (49707))
    - General data - Includes grants [2 folders], 1952-1959 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Planning, 1952-1955 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Planning - Letter from Adler to Faust - Outline of work, 1956 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Planning - Research on Freedom - Comments, 1954-1955 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Publications - "The Capitalist Manifesto", 1957-1958 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Publications - "The Controversy Concerning Human Freedom, Parts I-IV" [3 Folders, Includes bibliography], 1953 (Box 1 (49707))
    - Publicity [Photographs], 1952-1953 (Box 1 (49707))
      - [Photographs], 2015.014.001 (Box SF3)
    - Report - Biennial, 1956-1958 (Box 1 (49707))
  - Management Survey, 1951-1959; 10; 9.6 Cubic Feet 8 boxes.; 8 boxes.
    The Management Survey sub-series consists of files relating to an administrative survey and evaluation of colleges and universities. The files contain general data and summary reports from participating institutions.
    - General correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 1 (49708))
    - General correspondence with schools, 1954-1956 (Box 1 (49708))
    - General data [2 Folders], 1952-1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Pamphlet, 1952-1954 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Publicity, 1953-1958 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Report - Management Improvement in American Colleges and Universitites - Millet, John D. (Box 1 (49708))
    - Atlanta University Center - Grant, 1952 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Atlanta University Center - Reports [3 Folders], 1953-1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Austin College - Grant, 1953-1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Austin College - Reports [2 Folders], 1952 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Barnard College - Grants, 1952-1953 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Barnard College - Report, 1952 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Bennett College - Grants, 1954 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Bennett College - Report, 1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Bowdoin College - General, 1953-1954 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Bowdoin College - Report, 1953-1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Brandeis University - General, 1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Brandeis University - Grants, 1955-1956 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Coker College - General data, 1953-1959 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Coker College - Grants, 1953-1955 (Box 1 (49708))
    - Connecticut College - Grant, 1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Connecticut College - Reports, 1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Cornell University - Grant, 1953-1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Davidson College - Grant, 1952-1954 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Davidson College - Reports [2 Folders], 1952-1953 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Denison University Grants [3 Folders], 1952-1953
    - Drexel Institute of Technology - Grants, 1954-1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Drexel Institute of Technology - Reports, 1956 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Earlham College - Grant, 1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Earlham College - Reports, 1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Georgetown College - Grants, 1953-1954 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Georgetown College - Reports, 1954 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Goucher College - Grant, 1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Hamilton College - Grants, 1953-1955 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Hamilton College - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 2 (49709))
    - Lake Forest College - Grants, 1953-1954 (Box 3 (49710))
    - Lake Forest College - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 3 (49710))
    - Lincoln University - Grants, 1954 (Box 3 (49710))
    - Manhattan College - Grants, 1955 (Box 3 (49710))